放轻松
Easy, now.
放轻松 小伙子们
Easy, boys.
好啦 放轻松
Easy, now.
出什么事了?
What the hell?
紧急警报 紧急警报 我们这儿有情...
Code red. Code red. We got a sit...
(安全系统被破坏 紧急警报)
长官 周边地区被突破
Sir, we have a breach in the perimeter.
全部进入警戒状态! 清空所有硬盘数据 进入一级戒备
Go secure. Sweep the hard drives. Lock us down.
(一级戒备)
到处都是红外线影像 所有的走廊都是他们的人
Heat signatures everywhere. They've covered all the halls.
看来我们要来个"大清洗"了
Then I guess we better clear the halls.
行动!
Go!
马上疏散!
Evacuate! Now!
来吧只要你敢走出那扇门 我让你好看
Come on. I dare you to come walking through that door. Come get some.
钥匙
Keys.
- 我们到底惹了谁了 长官? - 上车
- Who the hell did we piss off this time? - Get in.
- 这玩意儿带武器吗? - 当然
- This thing armed? - Always.
好样的
Good man.
你见过这种东西吗?
You ever seen one of these?
做梦见过
Only in my dreams.
微型热像仪 水中数据传导器 480转
Geothermal micro cam, Aquacade uplinks, 480 gigs.
这玩意儿比国家安全局的还先进十倍
Sir, this thing is 10 generations beyond the NSA.
那就是说不管谁袭击了我们 都是有备而来的
So whoever attacked us is loaded for war.
而且很清楚从哪下手
And they knew exactly where to hit us.
我们现在要找个接班人了
We gotta go off the grid now.
不会再是什么溜冰 滑板 或者自行车之类的
Not another skater, snowboarder or biker.
新一代的XXX要更有危胁
The new XXX has gotta be more dangerous.
更致命更有型
Deadlier. More attitude.
更有型?
More attitude?
我们到哪儿才能找到这种人啊?
Where the hell are we gonna find that?
《极限特工2：极限公国》
您中午要和国家环保署开会
You have a meeting with the EPA at noon...
- ...讨论... - 他们只有那个能耐
- ...to discuss... - A tree is a tree.
还能指望他们多考虑什么呢?
How many more can they look at?
您的周年纪念日 要玫瑰还是郁金香?
Your anniversary, roses or tulips?
乔治郁金香 黄色的谢谢
George. Tulips, yellow. Thank you.
国安局的一个分部刚刚被袭
An NSA chapter was just hit.
死了十六个特工
Sixteen agents, all dead.
十六个我们的人?
Sixteen of our men?
在我们自己的地盘上? 怎么会发生这种事儿?
On our own soil? How the hell did this happen?
我正在调查
I'm looking into it.
- 有嫌疑对象吗? - 太多了
- Suspects? - Too many.
这件事需要我操心吗?
How concerned do I need to be?
我会处理的 干净利落而且保密
I'll take care of it. Quick and clean. And contained.
真该死 居然死了16个!
Goddamn it, 16 men?
还会死多少?
How many more have to die?
预算会议取消
This is no longer a budget meeting.
国防部长刚刚通知我
The secretary of defense has just informed me...
有16个国家安全局特工被杀了
...that 16 of our NSA agents were killed.
就在弗吉尼亚州
ln Virginia.
嫌疑犯几乎遍布半个世界
This is a laundry list of suspects that covers half the world.
是该改变政策的时候了
lt's time for a new direction.
新的军事财政预算是新政策的关键
The new military bill is critical to that direction.
所以 这将写入我这星期发表的国情咨文
So it's going in my State of the Union address this week.
(美国军事监狱 最高警戒区)
请让我们单独待一会儿 律师会面 有这个特权
Some privacy, please. Attorney-client privilege.
很高兴再次见到你 上尉
Good to see you again, lieutenant.
已经多久了? 9年?
How long has it been? Nine years?
还不够久
Not long enough.
而且不许再叫我上尉
And don't call me "lieutenant."
我现在是3655号
I'm inmate 3655 now.
你来这儿干什么 吉本斯? 你想要什么?
What you doing here, Gibbons? What you want?
要你我要给你个工作
You. I wanna give you a job.
我为什么要为你做这个狗屁工作?
And why would I do a damn thing for you?
你见过动物园的狮子吗?
You ever see lions at the zoo?
你总分辨出那些从野外抓获的...
You can always tell the ones that were captured in the wild...
...只要看它们的眼睛就行了
By the look in their eyes.
天啊 你还是这套狗屁说词
Jesus Christ. You still coming with that same sorry-ass speech?
起过作用吗?
Does it ever actually work?
- 有时候有用 - 至少这回不行
- From time to time, yeah. - Not this time.
我这两天不怎么爱国
I'm not feeling too patriotic these days.
所以 我不会加入你的这个小战争
So I want no part of your little war.
你已经加入了
You're already part of it.
有人在杀害我们的旧战友
Somebody's taken out members of our old unit.
他们既然找了我 也会来找你的
They came for me. They will come for you.
你要么死在这里 要么和他们打一仗
Now, you can die in here, or you can take the fight to them.
我记忆中的德瑞斯总是会先出手
The Darius I remember always liked to throw the first punch.
这些说词是新的了吧?
New speech, huh?
你在里面有自由活动吗?
You get any exercise in here?
每天12点到1点 在院子里
Twelve to 1 every day on the yard.
明天12:06
12:06 tomorrow.
- 德尔塔高地见 - 高地?
- Bravo Delta High Sign. - High Sign?
高地 就像以前一样
High Sign. Be just like old times.
最好和以前不一样
You better hope not.
因为上次结果可不怎么好
Because last time out didn't have such a happy ending.
你失踪了 而我进了这里
You went MlA, and I ended up in here.
好了 闭嘴
Okay, wrap it up.
嘿
Hey.
你的脸弄得不错 我喜欢
I like what you did with your face.
好了 我们走
Come on, let's go.
总部来了报告
There's been a report from home office.
桑迪·基斯昨晚在博拉博拉岛被杀了
Xander Cage was killed in Bora Bora last night.
博拉博拉岛?
Bora Bora?
为什么不能分配我到那些岛去工作?
Why don't I get those assignments, huh?
吉本斯怎么样了 谁有他的消息?
What about Gibbons? Any word on Gibbons?
未予说明 只知道这个
Unaccounted for. We do know this:
只有三个人能用那个电梯 而他是其中一个
He was one of only three men with access to that elevator.
另外两个
The other two....
已经不能提供更多的线索
Ain't gonna be giving us much of a statement.
好的 全面调查吉本斯先生 盯紧点
All right, put Mr. Gibbons on the wire. Full recon. Wrap it tight.
A区犯人进入练习场
A-Block to exercise yard.
溜狗时间到了
Time to take the dog out for a walk.
知道吗...
You know...
- 我真的会很想你们的 小伙子们 - 什么?
- ...I'm gonna really miss you boys. - What?
- 关掉所有的门! - 犯人 趴下!
- Secure all doors! - Prisoner, stand down !
- 六级戒备! - 把援助找来!
- Level six, lockdown ! - Get backup up here!
犯人 趴下!
Prisoner, stand down !
抓住他!
Get him !
- 洗衣房! 西面的门 - 马可!
- Laundry! West door! - Marco!
瞄准好了250码
Got him. Two hundred and fifty yards.
他要去哪儿? 他不可能靠近墙
Where's he gonna go? He's nowhere near the wall.
好了 兄弟!
All right, man !
- 抓住他! - 抓住!
- Get him ! - Hold it!
回来!
Come back!
你们迟到了!
You were late.
你确定是这样子接人吗 长官?
You sure know how to pick them, sir.
这个家伙是谁?
Who the hell is this guy?
文官
Civilian contractor.
等他醒过来的时候 我们早走了
By the time he wakes up, we'll be long gone.
- 你说了是12:06 - 遇到气流
- You said 12:06. - Hit some turbulence.
- 我们有大号和超大号 - 你是谁 男管家?
- We got large and extra large. - Who are you, the butler?
托比·李·杰弗 华盛顿技术分部
Toby Lee Shavers, D.C. Tech Division.
- 德瑞斯·斯通 监狱A区 - 再也不是了
- Yeah. Darius Stone, cellblock A. - Not anymore.
德瑞斯·斯通不存在了
Darius Stone no longer exists.
- 那我是谁? - 你是新的XXX
- Well, who the hell am I? - You're the new XXX.
听上去像是演A片儿的
Sound like a porno star.
- 那原来的XXX呢? - 死了
- What happened to the old XXX? - He's dead.
XXX是我们给身怀绝技的卧底特工起的名字
XXX is the designation we give to deep-cover agents with special skills.
好吧 随便了先说重点
Yeah, whatever. First things first.
我在里面待了很长时间了
I've been on the inside a long time.
我需要任何一个刚从监狱出来的男人都要的
I need what every man needs when he's coming off of lockdown.
你知道我的意思吧?
You know what I'm saying?
是的 宝贝 你老爸是谁? (饿得什么都不顾了)
Yeah, baby. Who's your daddy?
你确定他是你要的人吗?
You sure we got the right guy?
嘿 伙计! 再来份薯条和奶昔
Hey, buddy, more fries and another shake.
这就来
You got it.
- 开工了 - 我再要点薯条和奶昔
- We need to go to work now. - I need more fries and another shake.
嘿 你现在是在为我们干活
Hey, you work for us now.
- 所以你要... - 我想什么时候干活 就什么时候干
- So you're gonna do... - What I want when I want.
看好
Look...
我现在筋疲力尽 你们在那儿就违反了十条联邦法律
...by my count, you boys just broke about 10 federal laws back there.
协助罪犯逃跑 藏匿罪犯
Aiding and abetting, harboring a fugitive...
还有我喜欢的偷窃直升机
...and my personal favorite, grand-theft chopper.
- 那你的意思是? - 你们两个...
- So, what's your point? - That you two...
...现在是在"玩火"
...are looking at three strikes and the inside of a very small cell.
- 不要抢我的台词 - 现在我是主角
- You know that's my speech. - I'm running the show now.
咱们说好了我不会听你的
So here's the deal : I don't answer to you...
当然也不会听这个学生愣头青的
...and I damn sure don't answer to college boy.
学生愣头青?
College boy?
行
Done.
付账
Pay the man.
好 我们已经知道你会打架和吃饭 你还会什么?
Okay. So we know you can fight and eat, but what else can you do?
上一个XXX会滑雪 会冲浪 还有各种绝活
The last XXX, he could ski, surf, do all kinds of stunts.
但是他死了 不是吗?
Well, he's dead now, isn't he?
现在情况不一样了
So things are gonna be different around here.
因为我不会拿自己的命开玩笑
Because I don't play with my life.
- 要冒险 也先用你们的小命 - 我们得回华盛顿
- I'd rather play with yours. - We gotta get back to D.C.
我们需要找个地方躲一阵儿
We need a place to lay low.
我知道一个最安全的地方
I know the safest place in town.
这就是最安全的地方?
This is the safest place in town?
(神殿剧场)
别动 我会处理的
Stay put. I'll handle this.
德瑞斯·椎·斯通
D-Train Stone.
怎么样啊? 我听说 他们把你关在...
Heard they had you locked down in the deepest hole...
大峡谷最深的地洞里了
...this side of the Grand Canyon.
大概我表现太坏 所以他们不得已把我放了
Yeah, they let me out early for bad behavior.
- 伙计 真的是有一阵了 - 老板在哪儿 我要跟她谈谈
- Man, it's been a while, D. - Where's the boss? I need to talk.
你走了以后 很多事情都变了
Man, a lot's been changing since you left, D.
我现在是老板了
I run the chop shop now.
- 罗拉去哪里了? - 市郊
- Where's Lo? - Uptown.
市郊?
Uptown?
现在 这儿更象市郊
Now, this is more like it.
欢迎到西部 X
Welcome to the west side, X.
要想混出名堂 就得入乡随俗
You wanna run in these circles, you're gonna have to blend.
我从不随俗
I don't blend.
法拉利的迪诺车 力矩线大概在6400转每分钟
The Dino has the torque curve dropping off around 6400 rpm.
把喷射器的脉冲增加到10%
Dial down the injector pulse width by about 10 percent.
试试20
Try 20.
德瑞斯
Darius.
你看上去老了
You look older.
吃九年牢饭你也会这样
Nine years of bad food will do that to you.
九年了
Nine years.
要是我说错了 请指正 你是不是想回避20岁?
Well, correct me if I'm wrong, but isn't that a few years shy of 20?
干脆你直接说你要什么吧 这样我们能快点
Just tell me what you need so we can do this and be done.
那才是你来的原因 对吧? 你到底需要什么
That is why you're here, right? You need something.
热水澡 还有个地方睡一觉
Hot shower, place to crash.
德瑞斯 看看四周
Look around, Darius.
我在这儿的生活不错
I've got a good life here.
我这次不会让你破坏我的生活的
And I'm not gonna let you wreck it this time.
好了
So...
需要我干什么?
...what's in it for me?
67款GTO汽车
'67 GTO.
1000马力的 特殊悬浮系统
Thousand horsepower, crate motor, trick suspension.
- 什么? - 他说的是
- What? - He's right.
- 他们会找它的 - 另外 我们还需要...
- They'll be looking for it. - Besides, if we're gonna roll...
一个有力量的东西
...we're gonna need something with a little more muscle.
有威胁的(与"淫荡"同音)
Something nasty.
这个我可以哦
I can do nasty.
我知道你办得到
I know you can.
加粗倾斜滚珠轴承 8升油缸
Bored and stroked, full roller, 8 liters.
每平方英尺25磅的增压器
Supercharged with a 25-psi boost, automated hydraulics...
自动液压系统 带变速箱 你觉得如何?
...high-stall converter with shift kit. That gonna do the trick?
- 你满意啦? - 不错
- You happy? - I'm good.
我喜欢这姑娘
I love this girl.
目标? 就是情报
All right, the target is information.
在我以前那个司令部的硬盘上
lt's on a hard drive inside my old headquarters, here.
剩下的在我家里
The rest of it is at my house.
- 我今晚拿给你 - 信息?
- I'll pick that up tonight while you... - lnformation?
先给我点信息啊
Well, start by giving me some.
- 我们知道的一样多 - 你知道我指的是什么
- We on the same page? - You know what I'm talking about.
上一次我被捕 可是你消失了
Last time out, I went down, and you disappeared.
听着 那天不只是你有损失
Look, you aren't the only one who lost something that day.
当时起火了 而你正忙着和将军交战
When the fire started, you were busy with the general.
我们中的一些人就冲进去了 看还能救出谁
Some of us went in to see who we could save.
现在你觉得这样不好了? 你应该看看我收拾完之前的烂摊子
Now, you think this looks bad? You should've seen it before I got it fixed.
看来大概没有谁的经历是愉快的
Guess nobody's story has a happy ending.
这一切都还没结束呢 大兵
Story's not over yet, soldier.
杰弗
Shavers...
你能把这个改装成单兵用枪吗?
...can you make that into a personal weapon?
给我一个小时
Give me an hour.
- 我们之间还有问题吗? - 上校 很有趣的是
- We straight? - lt's funny, captain.
战争打打停停 而我的战士们却是永恒不变的
Wars come and go, but my soldiers stay eternal.
我喜欢这句话 是谁说得来的?
I like that. Who said it?
- 杰弗逊? 巴顿将军? - 图帕克
- Jefferson? Patton? - Tupac.
好吧 X 这是一次绝密行动
All right, X, this is a covert op.
绝对机密
Full stealth, total silence.
你一定要非常仔细
You're gonna wanna be real delicate here.
精巧
Subtle.
非常精巧
Very subtle.
这是14区
This is sector 14.
上面被袭击了
We got an attack, topside.
你们两个守住这一层 其他人跟我走!
You two, hold the floor. Everybody else, follow me.
好的 X 你有三分钟
All right, X, you got three minutes.
X 吉本斯的办公室在西北角第四区
X, Gibbons' office is northwest corner, sector four.
喂 等等!
Hey! Wait!
X 主房间
X, main room.
取出面朝你的三个硬盘的第一个
Remove the first of three drives facing you.
这里没人
There's nobody here.
除了所有我们的人
Yeah, except for all of us.
这不是袭击 是调虎离山
lt wasn't an attack, it was a diversion.
好了 X他们回来了 你必须离开! 快!
All right, X, they're coming back down. You gotta go. Now.
包围这里
Lock this place down.
要活捉
I want him in hand, alive.
大学生小子! 我被截住了! 把我弄出来!
College boy, I'm cut off. Get me out of here.
好的 X 去码头 前面1/4英里
Okay, X. Boat dock, quarter mile, dead ahead.
截住那卡车
I want that truck.
封锁方圆十英里以内的每条道路
Block every road in a 10-mile radius.
有人受伤吗?
Everybody okay?
我车丢了 船也没了
Blows up my car, he blows up my boats.
这家伙到底是谁?
Who the hell is this guy?
好啦 大学生小子我正在笔直朝前赶
All right, college boy, I'm headed upstream.
X 我这儿出了点小状况
X, got a little bit of a problem here.
有警察!
This is the police.
妈的 你的任务不过是开开车而已
Goddamn ! All you had to do was drive.
你知道吗 X 我真的开始想念以前的XXX了
You know what, X? I'm really starting to miss the old XXX.
马上停车!
Stop your vehicle now.
好的 我看见你了!
Okay, I see you.
从驾座上滚开!
Hey, get your ass out the driver's seat.
任务完成
Mission accomplished.
德瑞斯·斯通 出生在华盛顿南部 早年丧母 由父亲养大成人
Darius Stone. Born south side, D.C. Mother died young, father raised him.
生活很普通 一直到1988年
Not much to report till '88.
他的父亲被街头流弹打死 然后德瑞斯就不上学了
His dad was killed by a stray bullet in a 211, and Darius went off the grid.
开始是小偷小摸 野蛮驾驶
Started with graffiti, reckless driving.
因为偷车拘捕被抓
Quickly worked his way up to grand-theft auto and resisting arrest.
过了一段时间以后 他参加了海军 如鱼得水
Took him some time to find his calling in the Navy.
特别是在加入美国海军特种部队以后
Specifically, the Navy SEALs.
受训成为狙击手 成绩优异 擅长城市作战 爆破
Trained sniper, top scores. Urban recon, demolition.
保持海军最高潜水纪录250英尺
The highest dive in Navy history, 250 feet.
奥古斯塔斯·吉本斯招他入了精英组
Augustus Gibbons recruited him into an elite unit, Level 5 Classified.
特选到科索沃执行任务 一年圣诞节
Ran ops in Eastern Europe till Christmas in Kosovo.
他们的将军下令放火来铲除平民
Their general ordered them to set a fire to clear civilians...
但是斯通拒绝执行 并领导了对这位四星将军的兵变
...but Stone refused. Led a mutiny against a four-star general...
而这个将军就是现任国防部长乔治·德克
...the current secretary of defense, George Deckert...
他使斯通被判了20年刑
...who had him court-martialed for a 20-year term.
十年因为违抗军令
Ten for disobeying direct orders...
十年因为被斯通打坏了下巴
...and another 10 for breaking the general's jaw.
这是他最近的录像
This is the last footage we have on him.
和他的律师乔纳森·爱德华·卡伦的会面
A meeting with his lawyer, Jonathan Edward Cochran.
真有意思
Oh, that's cute.
强尼·卡伦
Johnnie Cochran.
我可不认为斯通先生能付得起强尼的律师费 我们有录音吗?
I don't think Mr. Stone can afford Johnnie's fee. Do we have audio?
律师会面 不能录音
lt's attorney-client. No mikes.
停 倒回去
Hold it there. Okay, reel it back.
倒 倒 倒 停
Back, back, back. Freeze it.
放大
Blow it up.
吉本斯和斯通卷土重来了
Gibbons and Stone on a comeback tour.
好的 听好 我要你们全力以赴看好这两个人
All right, listen up. I want all eyes up and running on these two.
而且我要你们调查他们的旧部属
And I want hard 20s on the rest of their old unit.
我要知道他们在哪儿
I wanna know where they are...
我要知道他们在干什么 我现在就要 越快越好
...I wanna know what they're doing, and I wanna know now.
我很失望 奥古
I'm disappointed, Auggie.
三步之内将你的军?
Checkmate in three?
你本该预料的到的
You should've seen it coming.
放轻松 喝一杯
Relax. Have a drink.
- 我冒昧自己倒了些 - 你从来不懂得客气
- I took the liberty of pouring myself... - You were always taking liberties.
你还是老样子啊
Same old Gibbons.
坏脾气的好军人
Good soldier with a bad attitude.
你知道吗 我一直记得我们第一次见面
You know, I always remember the first day we met.
我会记得我们最后一次的见面!
I remember the last day I saw you.
我敢打赌你一定会的
I bet you do.
还没痊愈 是吧
Didn't heal too well, did it?
有些伤口永远好不了
Some wounds never do.
- 我从来没要你冲进那场大火 - 是没有 你只是坐在那儿看着它烧
- I never asked you to go into that fire. - You just set it and watched it burn.
我们只不过做了我们该做的事
We did what needed to be done.
这就是你的说词? 做我们该做的事?
Is  that what you call it? "Doing what you need to do"?
我的人死了十六个 怎么回事 只是因为一起无恶意的大火吗?
Sixteen of my men killed? What's that, just more friendly fire?
总要有人舍身取义
Some men die so others may live.
可笑
Funny...
舍身的从不是你
...that you never seem to be the one doing any of the dying.
只要能最好的保卫这个国家 我什么都肯做
I'll do whatever it takes to best protect this nation.
你这样做不是在保卫国家 你是在保卫你自己!
You're not protecting the nation. You're doing this to protect yourself.
- 什么? 你现在正在进行什么样的战争? - 我们都生活在同样的世界
- Why? What fires you starting now? - We both live in the same world.
- 我们知道外面的世界是什么样的 - 别浪废你的吐沫了
- We know what's out there. - Save the speech.
告诉你
Just so you know...
不管你想干什么 你都别想逃脱
...whatever you're up to, you're not getting away with it.
怎么?
Why?
因为德瑞斯会阻止我?
Because Darius Stone is gonna stop me?
请原谅我
I'm sorry.
我是不是应该很吃惊?
Was that supposed to be a surprise?
吉本斯 你的每一招我都料到了
Gibbons, I know every move you make even before you do.
不管知道不知道 你都是在给我卖命!
You still work for me, whether you know it or not.
我从不为你卖命!
I never worked for you.
- 我为国家卖命 - 不知道哪个更可悲
- I work for my country. - I don't know what's more pathetic...
一个跟自己下象棋的人
...a man that plays chess with himself...
还是一个不知道自己已经输了的人
...or a man that doesn't see he's already lost.
制造成一个意外 不要泄露机密
Make it look like an accident. Zero exposure.
长官 他们找到了吉本斯
Sir, they found Gibbons.
"调查人员称这是一起明显的 煤气泄漏导致的大爆炸
lnvestigators say an apparent gas leak triggered the explosion.
消防人员未能及时救出住户
The fire department was too late to save the occupant...
但是及时遏制了火势蔓延
...but managed to contain the fire before it spread.
死亡者奥古斯塔斯·吉本斯是前海军上校
The deceased, Augustus Gibbons, was a former Navy captain.
享年51岁
He was 51 years old.
葬礼将于明天举行 地点是阿林顿国家公墓
The funeral's tomorrow at Arlington National Cemetery.
煤气泄漏 对
Gas leak. Right.
这里是MJLA电视台的 利萨·乔伊纳带给您的报道
This is Lisa Joyner reporting from Chevy Chase, Maryand for WJLA.
切回演播室
Back to you in the studio.
托比 开始干活吧
Toby, let's get to work.
里面什么都没有
There's nothing on here. Nothing.
没有是空的 伙计
lt's blank, man.
因为你找错地方了
Because you're looking in the wrong place.
吉本斯说就在硬盘上
Gibbons said it was on the hard drive.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
我读过关于这方面的东西
I read about that.
冷战时的老花招了 对吧?
Cold War. Old school, right?
不是那个时候的
Not that old school.
(查理 六月24号 星期三 参议院会议 MTS部)
好
All right.
那谁是查理?
Now, which one's Charlie?
只有一个办法才能知道
Only one way to find out.
瞄准!
Ready. Aim.
射击!
Fire.
准备 瞄准 射击!
Ready. Aim. Fire.
持枪立正
Order arms.
正如我们的上帝和救世主
Like our Lord and savior...
奥古斯塔斯·尤金·吉本斯去了...
...Augustus Eugene Gibbons died in our service.
那是国家安全局 联邦调查局 参谋长联席会议成员 国防部部长
Head of the NSA, FBI, Joint Chiefs, secretary of state.
妈的
Damn.
你知道这意味着什么 对吧?
You know what this means, right?
- 什么? - 他们下一个就要杀我了
- What? - They're gonna kill me next.
- 把望远镜给我 - 妈的 伙计
- Give me those. - Damn, man.
如果我们在一起合作 你就要稍微改变一下你的态度 像个搭档的样子
If we're working together, you should work on your partner skills.
比如你要什么东西 要说 能否请你 借给我那个东西?
Like, if you want something, try "Please," "May I borrow...?"
能否请你 把望远镜借给我
Please, may I borrow the binoculars...
不然我就打得你满地找牙?
...before I kick your teeth in?
好的 这是个好的开始还不错
Okay. See, now, that's a start. Not bad.
- 德克? - 你认识国防部长德克?
- Deckert? - You know Secretary Deckert?
哦 对
Oh, yeah.
我们又绕回来了
We go way back.
他恨死吉本斯了
But he hated everything about Gibbons.
他在这里干什么?
So, what is he doing here?
- 查理 - 你找到他了
- Charlie. - You found him.
她
Her.
- 她? - 能给我套西装吗?
- Her? - Can you get me a suit?
哦 你现在想随俗了
Oh, so now you wanna blend.
我听说这儿有城里最好的秋葵汤
I hear this place has the best gumbo in town.
对不起
Excuse me.
我已经和别人约好了 在这儿共进午餐
I'm actually meeting someone for lunch.
放轻松 查理 只耽误你一分钟
Relax, Charlie. This'll only take a minute.
你怎么知道我的名字? 你是?
How did you know my name? Who are you?
我们有个共同的朋友
We have a mutual friend.
奥古斯塔斯·吉本斯
Augustus Gibbons.
是"曾经" 有同样的朋友
Had a mutual friend.
但是你还没回答我的问题呢
And you didn't answer my question.
你是?
Who are you?
我是德瑞斯·斯通
My name is Darius Stone.
斯通?
Stone?
全世界都在找你
You have half the suits in this city looking for you.
你来这儿干吗?
Why in the world would you come here?
相信我
Trust me...
没人会到这种地方找像我这样的人
...they won't look for a guy like me in a place like this.
无意冒犯你 不过我现在谁都不相信
Well, no offense, but I don't trust anybody right now.
好 这说明我们有共同点
Good. That means we got something in common.
查理 很抱歉我迟到了
Charlie. I'm sorry I'm so late.
城市青少年会议开的久了
I had that urban-youth meeting. lt ran over.
我给孩子们...
We're trying to set up that after-school...
在课后上关于枪只指导性的课程
...gun-instructiona program for kids and...
对不起 迪克·安德鲁 国家档案登记处工作 你好
I'm sorry. Dickie Ambrose, NRA. Hi.
比利·鲍勃·贝克 南部浸礼会教派兄弟会的
Reverend Billy Bob Baker, Southern Baptist Brotherhood.
很高兴见到你 教士
Well, it's just great to meet you, Reverend.
嘿 我们下个礼拜在北部有集会
Hey, listen, we're setting up this rally upstate next week...
我在考虑有没有办法
...and I was just wondering if there was some way we could attract...
吸引像你这样有名望的美国黑人参加
...you know, some upstanding African-Americans like yourself.
有什么建议吗?
You got any advice for us?
好的 迪克 也许你可以叫你的会员们
Well, Dick, perhaps you could tell your members...
别再买乡村音乐 别再烧十字架
...to stop buying country music, stop burning crosses...
别再射杀黑人
...and stop shooting black folks.
听清楚了没?
Hear me?
要是还不行的话
Now, if that don't work...
就试试免费送一些食品
...try a cookout with free food.
炸薯条更好
Preferably fried.
迪克
Dick...
你不会介意我们改天再...
...would you mind terribly if we rescheduled?
我想那样会...
I think that would be....
没关系 我有很多事干
Yeah, that's fine. I have a lot of stuff to do.
- 教士 我... - 给我打电话
- Reverend, I'll... - Call me.
我会打电话给你 讨论这件事的
I'll call you about that.
你跟上校的关系是?
Tell me about you and the captain.
我是吉本斯的国会联系人
I was Gibbons' contact on the Hill.
军事行动委会的助理之一
I'm an aide to the Senate Subcommittee on Military Action.
军方?
Military?
德克
Deckert.
国防部长德克?
Secretary of Defense Deckert?
什么事都瞒不过他
There's not a bullet shot in the dark that he don't know about.
查理 告诉我
So tell me something, Charlie.
你能不能帮我接近他?
Can you get me close to him?
好吧 教士
Well, Reverend...
你能找件燕尾服穿上吗?
...you think you can lay your hands on a tuxedo?
你成功了
You made it.
我可从不会错过这种派对
You know, I never miss a party.
我印象中可没见你穿过那种燕尾服
Not quite the tux I had in mind.
是 我现在暂时委曲一下
Yes, but I'm blending.
看到嘉宾了?
You see the guest of honor?
那些保镖?
Those bodyguards?
保镖是海军四队的 我们队一半的人都在这儿
SEAL Team Four. Half my old unit.
是渣滓的那一半
And not the better half.
跟他说话的那个丑将军是谁?
Who's the ugly general he's talking to?
杰克·皮特邦 参谋长联席会副主席
Jack Pettibone. Vice chair, Joint Chiefs.
- 看上去不怎么开心 - 音乐的关系
- Doesn't look too happy. - Must be the music.
唯一的解释
One way to find out.
我真不敢相信我所听见的
I truly can't believe what I'm hearing.
我们有三十年交情 杰克
We go back 30 years, Jack.
一起玩命 一起摸爬滚打 你从未质疑过我的命令
Same blood in the same mud, and you never questioned my command.
我想你肯定听说过美国国会 (国会不会坐视不理)
I presume you've heard of the United States Congress.
杰克
Jack...
这个国家正在向错误的方向发展
...this country is being led down the wrong path.
你真的觉得你能做的到 是吗?
You really think you can do this, don't you?
就凭着几个团的人
With just a few regiments.
一旦我们领头 整个军队都会跟着干
Once we lead, the full force will follow.
时间不等人
The clock is ticking.
不管你加入不加入
With or without you.
三天时间
Three days.
他在这
He's here.
黑人 白色燕尾服
Black guy, white tux.
宴会呆腻了?
Had enough of the party?
抓紧
Hold on.
你叫我追查他们的旧队友
You asked me to track down the rest of their old troop?
其中有一半人仍在服役
Well, half of them are still enlisted.
- 另一半呢? - 离队 失踪
- What about the other half? - Gone. Missing.
只要是反对德克的
The same men that backed Stone against Deckert.
每一个就这么消失了
Every single one of them just disappeared.
噢 噢 等等 这是你的家吗?
Wait a minute. This is your home?
对于一个参议员助理而言 干得很不错
Not bad for a senator's aide.
我不仅仅是个参议员助理 我还是参议员的女儿
I'm not just a senator's aide. I'm also a senator's daughter.
维吉尼亚州议员詹姆士·梅华特
James Mayweather, Virginia.
你老爸打算见我这样的人?
Think Daddy's ready to meet a guy like me?
- 实际上老爸不在城里 - 真的?
- Actually, Daddy's out of town. - Really?
请不要客气 德瑞斯
Make yourself at home, Darius.
我想你在这里生活的一定很舒服
Not a bad place to grow up, I guess.
表面上是
Only on the surface.
在华府政界长大 就跟成长在蛇窝一样
Growing up in D.C. politics is like living in a snake pit.
每个人都在为势力你争我夺
Everybody fighting for territory.
听上去跟我成长的环境一样
Sounds a lot like where I grew up.
这绝对不象我成长的环境
Oh, no. This is nothing like where I grew up.
换衣服吧 好不好?
Let's get you out of those clothes, shall we?
找到了
Here we go.
试试这些
Why don't you try these on.
这些不是我喜欢的类型
Not really my style.
何不去洗一个澡?
Why don't you go ahead and get cleaned up.
浴室有干净的毛巾
There's some fresh towels in the bathroom.
全套服务 对吗?
Full-service, huh?
如果你需要任何东西的话
You know, if you need anything...
我就在楼下大厅
...I'm just right down the hall.
任何东西?
Anything?
任何东西
Anything at all.
来点儿薯条和奶昔行吗?
How about some fries and a shake?
有些事可不是为国家做的
The things I can't do for my country.
查理?
Charlie?
查理
Charlie.
皮特邦?
Pettibone?
是她设的圈套
She set me up.
婊子!
Bitch.
警察
This is the police.
双手放于脑后 走出来
Come out with your hands behind your head.
参谋长联席会副主席就住在那里
We got the vice chair of the Joint Chiefs in there.
他在房子里面 有凶器 危险人物
The assailant is armed and dangerous.
必须非常谨慎行事 先生们
Proceed with extreme caution, gentlemen.
找一个人质谈判专家 封锁两条街区
Gus, get me a hostage negotiator, clear a two-block radius...
- 疏散周围五条街 - 最好疏散十条街
- ...and five is the active perimeter. - Better make that 10.
麦多上尉 这是特种部队的狙击手
Captain, the man's a Special Forces sniper.
一定要清场 至少一英里的范围
Keep all fields clear at least half a mile downwind.
- 你到底是谁? - 国家安全局 凯尔·斯蒂尔
- Who the hell are you? - Kyle Steele, NSA.
上校 我要跟这小子谈谈
Captain, I need to speak to this man alive.
- 谈什么? - 事关国家安全 先生
- So? - lt's a matter of national security, sir.
- 你到底要去哪儿? - 去里面
- Where the hell are you going? - Going inside.
我不管你是谁 只能给你六分钟
Listen, I don't care who you are. You got six minutes till we breach.
斯通!
Stone.
我进来了 没带枪!
I'm coming in unarmed.
好吧 把门关上
All right, close that door.
抬手!
Hands.
过来
Step forward.
你怎么知道你进门的时候我不会开枪?
How you know I wouldn't shoot you the second you stepped through?
我不知道
I didn't.
但是我知道 在他们破门而入之前 你只有五分钟
But I do know this: You got five minutes till they knock that door down.
废话少说
So let's skip the chitchat.
- 皮特邦在哪儿? - 楼上 死了
- Where's Pettibone? - Upstairs, dead.
- 你干的? - 要是我干的
- You do it? - If  I did it...
你是绝对不会知道的 除非我告诉你
...you wouldn't know until I wanted you to.
现在 转身
Now, turn around.
斯通 情况不妙
Stone, this doesn't look too good, man.
国家罪犯私闯民宅 手中持枪
An escaped convict breaks into a house with an automatic in hand...
- 楼上还有个死人 - 我没有私闯过去
- ...and a dead man upstairs. - I didn't break in.
过去
Now, move.
你没闯进来?
You didn't break in here?
难道是将军请你来小睡一下?
So, what, the general invited you over for a nightcap?
那么发生什么了? 你在玩枪时走火了?
What happened? You guys felt like playing Russian roulette?
这不是我的枪
This is not my gun.
指望我会相信你的鬼话?
You expect me to buy that line?
不是鬼话 是真相
lt's not a line, it's the truth.
- 他们设计陷害我 - 谁?
- They set me up. - Who set you up?
- 德克 - 德克
- Deckert. - Deckert.
国防部长德克
Secretary of Defense Deckert.
当吉本斯快找到真相的时候 德克杀了他
He clipped Gibbons when he got too close.
现在是皮特邦
And now Pettibone.
找到什么真相?
Too close to what?
斯通 还有3分钟
Stone, we have three minutes. Level with me.
我们为什么在这儿? 你为什么跟踪皮特邦?
Why are we here? Why'd you go after Pettibone?
我谁也没跟踪
I didn't go after nobody.
我都不认识他!
I don't even know the guy.
以前都没见过他
Never seen him before in my life.
哦 哦 放轻松
Easy.
看上去非常象是你干的
That sure looks a lot like you.
妈的 干得真绝
Damn, they're good.
现在是吃点心的好时候吗?
Think now is really the best time for a snack?
外面有三组人?
What they got out there, three teams?
闪光弹 防弹衣 热能探测器是这样吗?
Flash-bangs, body armor, heat-scopes. Am I close?
斯通 我想帮你 真的
Stone, I wanna help you here, I really do.
但是 你要跑了 你就真的有罪了
But if you run, you look guilty.
反正我长得就像罪犯
Brother, I was born looking guilty.
现在
And now...
是你走的时候了
...it's time for you to go.
他在哪?
Where is he?
上校 我找到他了 看起来他是在楼上浴室里
Captain, I got him. Looks like upstairs bathroom.
好的 去抓他
Okay, go get him.
"我们得到嫌疑犯的照片 我们知道..."
This is the last known photograph of the suspect.
- 照得不错 - 是 你挺上相
- Cute picture. - Yeah. Haircut suits you, definitely.
靠近夏洛茨维尔 维吉尼亚
...near Charlottesville, Virginia.
"预计袭击者有武器 很有威胁性"
The assailant is assumed to be armed and dangerous.
皮特邦将军的好友之一
One of General Pettibone's closest friends...
国防部长乔治·德克
... was Defense Secretary George Deckert.
杰克·皮特邦是我的挚友之一
Jack Pettibone was a dear friend of mine.
今晚我们国家失去了一个伟大的爱国者
And tonight, this nation has lost a great patriot.
国家也将会记住他的功勋
And his quiet contributions will be properly recorded...
他也会名垂青史
...in history books yet to be written.
"皮特邦将军的军队
From base to base, Camp Pendleton to Fort Bragg...
为了将军的葬礼
... General Pettibone's troops are en route...
在华盛顿集结"
... to Washington D. C. for the funeral.
他们不是为了葬礼而来
They're not coming for the funeral.
一丘之貉
Same blood, same mud.
皮特邦和德克并肩作战三十年
Pettibone and Deckert both served for over 30 years together.
那你的意思是皮特邦的军队也是
So that means Pettibone's troops are also...?
- 德克的 - 对
- Deckert's. - Correct.
这跟葬礼有什么关系?
What's that got to do with the funeral?
完美的遮掩德克制定的来宾名单
The perfect cover. Deckert does the guest list...
只有支持他的人会来
...only invites his boys to town.
这样一来 他自己的军队就建成了
He's got his army.
现在 他肯定已经装备好了 他从哪儿得到的军火?
Now, he's gotta be loading up. How would he get his gear?
只要去自己的部门就行 国防部
All orders go through his department, the DOD.
对
Right.
你要我闯进去?
You want me to hack in?
黑掉美国国防部?
To the U.S. Department of Defense?
那里有占地五百亩的硬件 超级CRAY计算机
We're talking 500 acres of hardware.
扩充的芯片
Cray supercomputers, encryption chips...
更别说比国家安全局 中情局 国税局加起来还多的防火墙
...not to mention more firewalls than the NSA, ClA and the lRS combined.
正是
Exactly.
拿着我的薯片
Hold my chips.
你不用陪我熬夜
You know, you don't have to wait up.
你以为我会丢下你一个人 和我的车在一起?
You think I'd leave you alone with my car?
这辆车有什么特别?
What's so special about this one?
是BlT COPER原型车 六百马力 一万转
Shelby Cobra prototype, 600 horses, 10,000 rpm.
只产三辆
Only three off the rack.
有个议员花了五十万买了一辆
And we sold it for half a mil to some senator...
开车从来没起超过一档
...who'll never take her out of first gear.
一辆车五十万?
Half a mil for a car?
你跟不上时代了 德瑞斯
You been gone a while, D.
现在什么都贵
Everything's more expensive now.
这我到是看出来了
I could see that.
过来
Come here.
干得真不错
You've done real good, Lo.
不用再运汽车 配零件 拆引擎
No rollbacks, part bins or stripped engines.
从齐克的小店铺发家 你现在简直不得了了
lt's a long way from Zeke's chop shop.
我后车厢里仍有零件
Still got a few bins in the back.
我还经常把自己的手弄的脏兮兮的
And I still get my hands dirty.
经典就是经典
Classic's still a classic.
还记得我们第一次开这个车的情景吗?
You remember the first time we dropped gears in this one?
我记得三辆警车在林荫道上追车 速度在100码以上
I remember three squad cars at 100-plus on the parkway.
她很快
Oh, she was fast.
真的 很快
Yes, she was.
记得我们把后车座搞得一团糟吗?
You remember all that damage we did in the back seat?
陈年旧事了 德瑞斯
That was a long time ago, D.
对我不是
Not for me.
可以再来一次吗?
Ready to do some more damage?
他成功了!
He shoots, he scores!
大学生小子成了本世纪最牛的黑客! 这里有份正式命令
College boy just pulled off the hack of the century. Requisition order.
德克准备把他所有的部队和军火
Deckert's bringing all his troops and armored vehicles...
都通过海军基地调到了独立号军舰
...through a naval base up the Potomac to the USS lndependence.
那可是个航空母舰
lt's an aircraft carrier, man.
看来我们要北上了
Looks like we going upstate.
哈哈 这不是我们的小姑娘嘛
Well, well. Daddy's little girl.
听我说 吉本斯 人们会相信...
Look, Gibbons, people will believe...
- 斯通 - 你想我吗?
- Stone. - You miss me?
当然罗 我们都想念你
Apparently, we all did.
她也让我上当了
She had me fooled too.
上校?
Captain?
哈里斯? 杰克森?
Harris? Jackson?
- 到底怎么回事? - 是你的旧战友 斯通
- What the hell is going on here? - lt's your old unit.
你也很快会加入他们
And you're gonna be joining them real soon.
- 她在说什么? - 德克我们都中了他的圈套
- What's she talking about? - Deckert. He set us up.
- 为什么? - 我不知道 我还没想出来
- For what? - I don't know. I didn't get that far.
我还以为你想出来了
I was hoping maybe you did.
- 你哪儿也别想逃 - 你也一样
- You not going nowhere. - Neither are you.
不 不 不 别管我们!
No, no, no. Don't worry about us.
你应该干掉那个婊子!
You know you should've killed that bitch !
- 谁拉的警报? - 斯通 他在这儿
- Who triggered the alarm? - lt's Stone. He's here.
列布 把那个家伙抓起来 然后带到这儿来
Liebo, get men fore and aft. Push him down here.
把他揪出来 马上!
Take him out now.
封住出口!
Seal the hatch !
你可以射击了 重复一遍 瞄的准一点!
You have green light. Repeat, take your best shot.
噢 中士 你还没升官?
Old Sergeant Cobb. You still too dumb to make captain.
斯通上尉 往日重现啊
Lieutenant Stone. Blast from the past.
我是你的斯通老爸
That's "Big Daddy Stone" to you.
跟我说说 坐牢的滋味还不错吧?
So tell me, how was prison?
你很快就知道了
You'll find out soon enough.
像你这样的嘴巴 他们会很喜欢的
And with a mouth like yours, they gonna love you on the inside.
快 快 瞄准!
Let's go, let's go. Get him.
开火!
Fire!
不好意思 是你的座驾吗?
Oh, I'm sorry, was that your ride?
不是 但是你的座驾会直接送你进地狱!
No, but yours is gonna take you straight to hell.
装弹
Loading.
准备
Stand by.
开火!
Now!
- 妈的! - 连边儿也没沾上
- Goddamn it. - Man, that wasn't even close.
下一步打算干什么? 把这儿全炸了?
Trucks, choppers. What's next? You gonna sink the ship?
只要你还在里面
Only if you're still on it.
给自己留点东西 不然你就一无所有了
Keep this up and you ain't gonna have nothing left, hillbilly.
- 上弹! - 完成!
- Load. - Loaded.
我们之间没完 乡巴佬
You and I have unfinished business, homeboy.
开火
Fire.
行动! 好 来吧上!
Move! All right, come on. Let's go!
- 嗨! - 他妈的 他在干什么?
- Hey! - What the hell is he doing?
你他妈的在干什么? 在那儿! 那边!
Where the hell you going? Over there. That way.
到最上边去 快!
Get that tank topside now.
快快快!
Move, move.
是B班的上飞行甲板 快!
Bravo Squad to flight deck now.
锁定目标!
Locked on.
开火!
Fire now.
妈的!
Goddamn it!
所有的潜水队马上潜水 封锁该区域
All dive teams in the water. Lock the area down.
一队 扫描船尾
Zodiac One, sweep the stern.
二队 扫描船中部右舷
Zodiac Two, starboard bow, in the midships.
搜索船一号和二号...
Search Boat One and Search Boat Two...
加强搜索范围 并注意码头
... widen your radius and search the port side.
潜水三队 报告进度
Dive Team Number Three, report any visual.
乔治 我今晚向全国发表国情咨文
George, I'm addressing the nation tonight.
新的军事财政预算会有什么问题?
So, what's the hang-up on the new military bill?
要是你一直缩减军队 关闭基地...
Well, if you're reducing troops, closing bases...
裁减国家海军局的话 会令我们的国家不堪一击
...and cutting R&D, you leave us vulnerable.
乔治 我们需要增加国际援助
George, we need to increase international aid.
我们必须扭转孤立局面
We need to reverse this isolationist doctrine.
也许我们能和一些国家化敌为友
Maybe then we can turn some of these enemies into allies.
我知道你不喜欢这一套 乔治
I know this doesn't particularly thrill you, George.
但是这会成为我留给后辈的遗产
But this is going to be my legacy.
- 先生 - 现在的问题是
- Sir. - Now, the question is:
你支持我吗?
Do I have your support?
毫无疑问 总统先生
lt goes without saying, Mr. President.
你的电话
Call for you.
是关于你订的新林肯车
lt's about the new Lincoln you ordered.
- 好 - 楼下
- Yeah. - Downstairs.
你的车 一个人过来
Your car. Come alone.
看一眼
Take a look.
- 这是国会大厦的地图 - 军事地图
- lt's a map of the Capitol. - A military map.
- 上面有袭击路线 袭击目标... - 我看到了
- With attack routes, targets... - I see that.
- 你从哪儿得来的? - 北区
- Where'd you get it? - Upstate.
从德克的小喽罗那儿 他们看来是想打第四次世界大战啊
Deckert's little boy scouts are gearing up for World War lV.
他们有坦克 直升机
They got tanks, choppers.
- 还有吉本斯 - 什么?
- They got Gibbons. - What do you mean?
吉本斯没死
Gibbons is not dead.
和一半我的旧队友关在一起
He's locked up with half my old unit.
- 北区? - 正确
- Upstate? - Correct.
德克要行动了 让吉本斯背黑锅
Deckert is setting them up for a fall.
- 什么黑锅? - 你觉得呢?
- Fall for what? - What do you think?
这家伙要袭击美国国会大厦
This man is making a move on the U.S. Capitol.
看见了吗?
See this?
我正在全局考虑
Map came from National Recon.
就算德克要行动的话
Yeah, Deckert's making a move. He's running security...
也是为今晚的国情咨文进行安全保障
...for the State of the Union tonight.
他不是要袭击 而是要保护这些目标
He's not attacking, he's guarding these targets.
真妙
Oh, that's beautiful.
掩盖的真漂亮
Perfect cover.
他把他的人已经分配到位
He's got his old crew suited and booted.
这些人只会进攻
Look, these boys don't play defense.
不会防御
Just offense.
证据不足
lt's not enough.
要是你的猜测错误呢?
What if you're wrong?
我的确错了
I was wrong.
我还以为你跟那些人不一样
I thought you was more than just another suit.
长官 安全人员名单
Sir, the security detail...
都是前军方的
...they're all ex-military.
是 我知道
Yeah, I can see that.
所有的人都曾是吉本斯和斯通的旧战友
All of them served with Gibbons and Stone.
- 应该是德克的旧部属 - 我想我们找到蛛丝马迹了
- lt's Deckert's unit. - Think we got something.
第四次世界大战
World War lV.
有什么事需要通知国防部吗?
Anything the Defense Department needs to know?
没有什么你不知道的 长官
Sure it's nothing you don't already know, sir.
- 乔治·德克 - 德克部长
- George Deckert. - Secretary Deckert...
这是斯蒂尔特工
...this is Agent Steele.
凯尔 部长想看看吉本斯案子的资料
Kyle, the secretary wanted to check in on the Gibbons case.
我个人对这个案子很有兴趣
I have a personal interest in the case.
吉本斯本是我的好友
Captain Gibbons was a friend.
我可以向你保证 我们在竭尽全力找他
Well, you can rest assured we're doing everything we can to find him.
- 找他? - 我们还没有确认他的尸体
- Find him? - You know, we never did lD his body.
像那样可怕的事故
Terrible thing, accident like that.
可能发生在任何人身上
Could happen to anyone.
凯尔 说吧 德瑞斯·斯通对你说了什么?
Tell me, Kyle, what did Darius Stone say to you?
- 不好意思 你是什么意思? - 在他消失之前
- What do you mean? - You were the last to talk to him...
你是最后一个跟他通话的
...before he got away.
他没说什么
He didn't say much.
不过是一堆不着边际的阴谋论 仅此而已
No, just a bunch of wild conspiracy theories, that's all.
听起来象是斯通的论调
Sounds like Stone.
好吧 要是你听到些什么...
Well, if you hear anything....
我会记下的
I'll know who to chase down.
长官 能告诉我一件事吗?
Sir, could you tell me something?
我一直在想...
I've always wondered...
你是如何挑选保护总统的人?
...how do you pick the men who protect the president?
很简单
Simple.
- 挑选我相信的人 - 象吉本斯
- I choose men I can trust. - Like Gibbons.
我们今晚要是有他的话就好了 长官
Would've been good to have him there tonight, huh, sir?
哦 他会在的他的精神与我们同在
Oh, he'll be there. ln spirit.
我相信他会的
I'm sure he will.
祝您好运 长官
Good luck, sir.
听上去右边的注入器比左边稀薄
Sounds like the right bank's running leaner than the left.
要想搞定它就必须调校电控器
You wanna richen her up, you're gonna have to remap the ECU.
- 很意外吗? - 是
- What, are you surprised? - Yeah.
你好象很会修卡车啊
Fact you know how to tune up a truck.
我以前可不是穿这种西装工作的
I didn't always wear a suit.
- 你怎么找到的我的? - 这是我的本行 德瑞斯
- How'd you find me? - lt's my job, Darius.
我很在行 聊聊?
I'm very good at it. Can we talk?
你没错
You were right.
德克知道吉本斯还活着 看看这个
Deckert knew Gibbons was alive. Look at this.
总统 副总统 白宫发言人 国务卿
President, VP, Speaker of the House, secretary of state.
所有的领导人 一旦干掉这些人 他就成了什么?
The chain of command. He takes them out, he's what?
- 德克就做总统了 - 没错
- Deckert becomes the new president. - That's right.
- 历史上最快的革命 - 是
- Cleanest revolution in history. - Yeah.
那你还在这儿干吗? 给白宫打电话阿
Why are you here? Call the White House.
不行我们不知道他的具体计划
Can't. We don't know how deep this goes.
那你的计划是?
So, what's your plan?
我想我们要找外面的人来干
Figure we gotta go outside the box on this one.
你打算找什么样的外人呢?
How far outside the box are you prepared to go?
因为如果要想靠近国会大厦
Because to get us close to the Capitol...
必须找些可靠的兄弟
...we're gonna need some brothers we can trust.
没有哪个地方比大本营更合适的了
Ain't no place like home.
是不是我听错了?
Man, y'all almost had me too.
说笑 你听到了?
They got jokes, man. You hear that?
- 天方夜谭 - 不是说笑
- They got jokes. - No joke.
- 我们需要你的帮助 - 那你们干吗不找警察?
- We need your help. - So why don't you go to the police?
- 不相信警察 - 这话我爱听
- We don't trust the police. - Heard that.
拿着 宝贝
Hold this, baby. One second.
你知道我们都支持你
Man, you know we got your back.
但这事跟我们没任何关系
But this ain't got nothing to do with us.
这个跟你们息息相关
This got everything to do with you.
不是为了美国而做 是为了你自己
Don't do it for the red, white and blue, do it for yourself.
为了你可以在白宫脚下
Do it for the right to hack and jack cars of the highest quality...
偷车改车的权利
...on the same block as the White House.
只不过这是美国的生活方式罢了 兄弟
lt's the American way of life, bro.
现在 如果你要捍卫这种生活方式的话
Now, if you wanna protect that way of life...
你必须站出来 为它而战
...then you gotta step up and fight for it.
因为要是德克掌权了 你就没有自由了
Because if Deckert takes over, freedom won't be free for long.
- 讲得不错 - 是啊
- Nice speech. - Yeah.
不过 说到自由的那段有点肉麻
The freedom part was a bit much, though.
我有点小要求 移民局 国税局那里
I got some federal heat. lmmigration, lRS.
有几个自家兄弟被处理的不大公正
Couple of homeboys unjustly accused.
我帮你这个忙 你帮我们?
I do this for you, you'll hook us up?
我会竭尽所能
I'll do what I can.
成交
Fair enough.
好的 伙计们 调整一下状态 有活儿干
All right, fellas, get your gear together. We got some work to do.
杰克 杀手 超人杰克 柴油机
Janky, Kevlar panels. Killa, super jacks.
拿上所有家当
Dizzle, heavy-duty roll cages.
伙计们 出发
Assholes and elbows, gentlemen. Let's go.
托比! 你来打理这些家伙 我们需要更好的装备
Toby. To deal with these guys, we're gonna need some serious gear.
看来是时候了!
Well, it's about time.
天啊 我真高兴听你这么说 X
God, I am so glad to hear you say that, X.
我给你做了些新玩艺儿 你一定会喜欢的
I got some stuff you're gonna love. Laser-scope...
激光频锁全球追踪仪
...frequency lock, GPS autotracker.
它可以分辨三十里以外...
This will tell you what perfume a chick's wearing...
- 辣妹的香水 - 这个早晚会用得上
- ...from 30 miles away. - That'll come in handy.
还有这些通讯干扰器 干扰发射台 电路千斤顶
So will these. Basic scramblers, jammers, circuit jacks.
所有你需要的 这是个特殊武器
Whatever you need. Now, this is the house special.
我管它叫顶级手套
I call this one The Glove.
没什么特别啊
So does everybody else.
当然不一样 它有电充气动吸力装置
Not everybody else has electro-charge pneumatic suction.
开启之后
Turn this bad boy on....
看到了?
See? Nothing.
可牢了 怎么扯都没用 喂 小心那个按钮 别...
Nothing at all. Chill out with the butt... Don't.
别...喂 喂 喂
Just... Hey, hey. Hey.
嘿 伙计 别玩了
Come on, man. Why you gotta play around here? Hey!
我们需要军火 你有什么能发射子弹的玩意儿吗?
We need firepower. Do you have anything that shoots bullets?
我没有但是国家安全局有
I don't, but Homeland Security does.
罗拉 快把我放下来
Lola. Come on, man, please.
好的 我去打个电话 看看五角大楼能不能送货
Okay. I'll just call the Pentagon and see if they deliver.
你不必那么做啊 他们一直在用民用卡车...
We don't have to. They've been running weapons across country...
运送武器
...in civilian trucks.
民用卡车?
Civilian trucks?
- 伙计 我饿了 - 五分钟前你刚吃过阿
- Man, I'm hungry. - You just ate five minutes ago.
到后面拿片干酪吃如何?
What if I go in the back and get a slice of cheese?
你才不会只吃一片呢
You'd stop at one slice.
国防部要一卡车干酪干什么啊?
What does Homeland Defense need with a truck full of cheese anyway?
是啊 你从未听说过"政府牌干酪"吗?
You ain't never heard of government cheese?
我们帮她们一把吧
Let's give them a little assistance.
- 小伙子们 你们好 - 姑娘们 热坏了吧
- Hi, boys. - Ladies. Look like you're overheated.
- 反正我们是热坏了 - 我的意思是 你们身材很火辣
- I know we are. - I mean your car.
我是不会任人宰割的!
I'm not going out without a fight.
- 他脑子有点问题 - 钥匙在卡车上
- He's retarded. - Key's in the truck.
把车停好 因为刹车有点失灵
Move the level, because the brakes get stuck.
嗨 联邦调查局侦探杰弗
Hi, I'm Agent Shavers.
我们今天要征用你的卡车
We'll be commandeering your truck today.
伙计 我们绝不能让别人知道 咱们让个白人给劫了
Man, we can't let nobody know a white guy hijacked us.
就说是75个黑人劫的
We'll say it was 75 black guys.
我们开卡车运枪 但是他们只付运干酪的钱?
We got a truck full of guns, they pay us to haul cheese?
- 不是干酪吗? - 你觉得如何 椎?
- That's not cheese? - So, what you think, D-Train?
火力够不够?
This enough bang for you?
上帝保佑美国
God bless America.
你要干掉总统 是吗 乔治?
You're going to take the president out, aren't you, George?
不是 上校 是你要 我扣扳机 你顶罪
No, captain, you are. They pull the trigger, you take the fall.
- 没人会相信的 - 什么?
- No one would ever believe l... - What?
奥库斯塔斯·吉本斯总是反对派
Augustus Gibbons always fought the system.
在这个星期 反对演变成了叛国
This week, that fight became a war.
他纠集了他的国家安全局旧部...
He took out his own NSA unit...
劫走重犯...
...broke a convict out of a maximum-security prison...
布下自己死亡假局 谋杀皮特邦
...staged his own death, ordered the murder of Jack Pettibone...
和他的叛军们作最后一击
...and rallied his old troop of traitors for one last stand.
我会相信的
I believe it.
你知道你的问题在哪儿吗?
You know what your problem is, Auggie?
你总是看得不够远
You've never been able to see beyond the bend.
而你从来就只看得到自己
And you've never been able to see beyond yourself.
你已经得到你那个英雄式的葬礼了 吉本斯
You've had your hero's funeral, Gibbons.
而这次 没有人会为你的死而祈祷
This time, they're gonna bury you in a pine box in an unmarked grave.
我还没死呢
I'm not buried yet.
上校 他只是孤家寡人
He's one man, captain.
一个人能做什么?
What can one man do?
德克已经封锁了所有街道
Deckert's got all the streets locked down.
封锁了所有方向的三个街区
Three blocks in every direction.
有些路 他是不知道的
There are some streets he don't know about.
在东部国会街
At the East Capitol and Eighth Street...
我们沿后巷穿过货仓到汽车站 混入国会区
...we use alleys and warehouses to bust out behind the Capitol.
- 会有坦克等着我们的 - 我来搞定坦克
- Gonna have tanks waiting. - Leave the tanks to me.
只要是有轮子的 我们就能偷
If it got wheels, we can jack it.
相信我
Trust me, daddy-o.
- 好的 出发 - 好的 先生们 整装待发
- All right, let's roll. - All right, gentlemen.
是结束的重大时刻了
Lock and load. Time to ride out.
自由国家的命运 居然掌握在一群偷车贼 维修工手里
The fate of the free world in the hands of a bunch of hustlers and thieves.
为什么今晚应该不同呢 (意思是 一直是这个样子的)
Why should tonight be any different?
正如您所看到的 在我身后 总统刚刚到达
As you can see behind me, the president is just arriving....
在总统今晚将要谈到的一系列议题中
The nation is eager to hear the president's stance on pressing issues.
新军事法案最为瞩目
Chief among them, the new military bill.
女士们先生们 欢迎美国总统
Ladies and gentlemen, the president of the United States.
美国民众们
Mr. Speaker, my fellow Americans...
今晚 我自豪地向各位宣布
...tonight I stand before you to report...
我们的国家非常强盛
...that the state of our Union is strong.
我们正处在一个关键时刻 我们手中...
We are at a critical moment in our history.
好
Nice.
"旷课乐" X 来吧 斯蒂尔 听听"旷课乐"(一种流行音乐)
Get crunk, X. Come on, Steele, get crunk with us.
我们需要勇气来重新审视
We now need the courage to reevaluate...
现代美国民主的进程
...the course of modern American democracy...
如果我们追求真正的繁荣富强
...if we are to truly flourish and survive.
前面好像有点小障碍
Looks like we got a little block party up ahead.
- 冲过去 - 坐好!
- Go through it. - Hold on.
我们必须用理解
We must use understanding...
和同情
...and compassion...
- 他们在向我们开枪! - 欢迎加入暴徒行列 学生哥
- They're shooting at us. - Welcome to the 'hood, college boy.
和妥协来赢得战争
...and compromise to win battles...
而不仅仅是牺牲...
...and not just the sacrifices...
年轻人的生命
...of the lives of our young men and women.
伙计们
Fellas...
我不想插手驾驶的事
...I don't mean to be a back-seat driver...
- 但是那个不是死路吗? - 没有死路这回事
- ...but isn't that a dead end? - There's no such thing as a dead end.
这就是我说的意思!
Now, that's what I'm talking about!
哦 妈的
Oh, shit.
快点倒车 快!
I think you might wanna back up right about now.
快快快
Go, go, go.
大家都下车 快!
Everybody out now.
- 我告诉过你 他们有坦克 - 我也说了只要有轮子
- I told you they'd have tanks waiting. - And I told you...
我们就能偷
...if it got wheels, we can jack it.
快! 把坦克搞定!
Move it. Get those jacks out of there.
欢迎 这是史上第一个被劫的坦克
Welcome to the first tank-jacking in history.
我们可以也必须竭尽全力
We can and must endeavor...
战胜敌人 令他们心服口服
...to win the hearts and minds of our enemies...
把他们变成我们的盟友
...and turn them into our allies.
因此 美国民众
And so, my fellow Americans...
我今晚要你们支持这个新的...
...I will ask you tonight to support this new...
- 怎么了? - 总统 您必须转移
- What's going on? - We need to move you.
待在座位上 没有特殊情况
Remain in your seats. No cause for alarm.
好 让我们操纵这些笨蛋零件上路吧
Okay, let's put these dubs to work.
你确定你会开坦克吗?
You sure you know how to drive this thing?
正在找感觉呢
Just trying to get a feel for her.
真过瘾! 我会习惯的!
Yeah ! I could get used to this.
最好有人把这个记下来
You know, somebody better leave a note.
好的 支开副总统
Okay, split off the vice president.
- 你在干什么? - 例行公事
- What are you doing? - Just following protocol, sir.
进入目标范围
We're in position.
紧急警报
Code red. Code red. Small-arms fire, Capitol building.
所有作战单位立即行动
All units respond immediately.
好的 齐克坦克是你的了
All right, Zeke, the tank is all yours.
嘿 你知道该怎么做吧
Hey, you know what to do.
我领队 你垫后
I'll take lead, you lay down cover.
喂 喂 你说你领队是什么意思?
What do you mean you'll take lead?
- 我才是XXX啊 - 是你 乔治?
- I'm XXX. - Is  this you, George?
是你干的?
Are you doing this?
你知不知道"叛国"这个词?
Are you familiar with the word "treason"?
你是杰斐逊的追随者 (独立宣言的起草人)
You're a Jefferson man.
自由之树时常需要...
"The tree of liberty must be refreshed from time to time...
爱国者的鲜血来灌溉
...with the blood of patriots."
还有独裁者的引用结束
"And tyrants." That's the end of the quote.
只要能保证这个国家的安全强大 我什么都肯做
I will do whatever it takes to keep this nation safe and strong.
同情? 理解?
Compassion? Understanding?
你生活在什么世界?
What world are you living in?
干掉他
Get rid of him.
好的 齐克 快干! 马上!
Okay, Zeke, do it. Do it now.
- 重新装修国会啦 - 看炮!
- Let's redecorate. - Fire in the hole.
二组正后方 一组正前方
Two Team, 6 o'clock. One Team, 12.
中士!
Sergeant.
把吉本斯带过来
Get Gibbons up here.
收到 正在路上
Roger that. We're on our way.
让我们结束这一切
Let's finish this.
- 枪法挺准 - 海豹队第一神枪
- Good shooting. - Navy SEALs. High scores, Coronado.
别吹了 我才是纪录保持者
Please. I got high score.
1996年被我破了
But I beat them in '96.
怎么 你不读新闻?
What, you don't read the newsletter?
从礼堂西南方切入 三十秒后与你会合
We're coming in from the southwest halls. We'll be with you in 30...
放下枪!
Drop it!
快! 我说了 放下枪!
Now! I said, drop it.
你他妈怎么这么慢才过来?
What took you so damn long to get here?
还是老样子也许我该把它贴回去
Same old Gibbons. Maybe I should put this back on.
"谢谢""见到你很高兴 斯通" 这样的话一句也没有
Don't get a "thank you" or a "happy to see you, Stone" or nothing.
看到了? 早就告诉你该干掉这个婊子
See? I told you you should have killed that bitch.
干得好! 干得好!
Bravo to Sub Team. Bravo to Sub Team.
只要有吉本斯 我们依然能赢
We can still make this work if we have Gibbons.
查理 你到底在哪?
Charlie, where the hell is he?
将军 我就在这儿
I'm right here, general.
三步之内将你的军 你本应该预见得到的
Checkmate in three. You should have seen it coming.
趁你还来得及 投降吧 乔治 游戏结束了
Give up while you still can, George. lt's over.
事情没有按照计划发展 是吧?
Things not going according to plan?
长官?
Sir?
中士 沿侧面走
Sergeant, sidearm.
我们撤退到火车上去
We'll fall back to the train.
将军 他一定有个备用计划 会是什么?
Captain, he's got to have a backup. What would it be?
地下三层有为紧急撤退准备的...
There's a presidential bullet train...
总统专用子弹头火车
...three stories down for emergency evacuation.
追过去 我们处理这边!
Go after him. We'll take care of this.
- 中士? - 你 你 下去!
- Sergeant. - You, you, out.
照他的命令做
Do what he says.
不!
No!
开车
Drive.
我告诉过你 我需要一个超级快车
Toby, I need a ride. Something fast.
听着 派三架黑鹰来 快!
Listen up. I want three Black Hawks on that pad, ASAP.
清除道路 我要车
Clear the road. I got a car incoming.
不要让其它人进入大厦
Stay clear of the building.
只有警卫和军队的人才可以进来
Only security and military personnel may enter.
是最后一击的时候了 中尉 抓住他
Time to throw the last punch, lieutenant. Go get him.
听说你要辆车
Heard you needed a ride.
所有的平民们 请留在原来的岗位上 直到所有的警报结束
All civilians, remain where you are until cleared by security detail.
她有多快?
How fast does she go?
你来告诉我
Let me know.
- 喂! - 斯蒂尔! 火车往哪儿开?
- Yeah? - Steele, where's that train going?
- 西北 直上州际95... - 收到
- North-northwest. Straight up l-95. - Got it.
- 德瑞斯 等一下! - 他不会等的
- Darius, wait a... - He's not a big fan of waiting.
我也不会 我们走
Neither am l. Let's go.
在那儿!
There it is.
再靠近点
Okay, get me closer.
再快点!
Faster.
坐下 吉姆
Sit down, Jim.
感觉不错 是吧? 打人的感觉
Feels good, doesn't it? To get your hands dirty?
操你妈的
Fuck you.
好吧 我们看看值五十万美金的家伙能做到怎样
Okay, let's see what half a million buys.
我没法瞄准!
I can't get a clean shot.
你不能 但他能
Maybe you can't, but he can.
他们追来了 乔治 你没地方躲了
They'll just keep coming, George. There's no way you're gonna hide.
为什么我要躲起来? 躲一个试图要救总统 却失败了的人?
Why should I hide? The man that tried to save the president but failed?
我会被视为爱国者的
I'll be seen as a patriot.
试着要救总统 你是说...
"Tried to save the president but..." You mean...?
国家的悲剧
A national tragedy.
这样看吧 你死后 说不定还会有个国家纪念日
Look at it this way: You might get your own holiday.
嘿 你需要点个火
Hillbilly, you need to lighten up.
- 手动刹车坏了 我没法减速 - 那我们就再也不需要你了
- Brakes are blown. I can't slow down. - We won't be needing you anymore.
行动
Move.
- 好的 准备好了! - 好的 开始行动
- Okay, ready. - All right, here we go.
丢下武器 踢过来 上尉!
Drop and slide, lieutenant.
没门
I don't think so.
没法稳定控制
Can't hold it steady.
趴下
Down.
跟以前一样 是吗?
Just like old times, huh?
是的 你的下巴怎么样 将军?
Yeah. How's that jaw, general?
我每次嚼东西的时候 都会想起你 斯通!
I think of you every time I chew steak.
而我在监狱里的每个晚上都会想起你!
And I thought of you every night I spent in prison.
走! 快跑!
Go! Run !
长官...
Sir...
你必须跳!
...you're gonna have to jump.
快进去了
Almost in.
我等这一天等了十年!
I've been waiting for this for 10 years.
那就继续等吧
Well, keep waiting.
是你为国牺牲的时候了 将军
Your turn to do the dying, general.
战争打打停停 而我们的战士却是永恒不变的
Wars come and go, but my soldiers stay eternal.
你说什么?
What's that you said?
好像有人该得到总统您的嘉奖 先生
Looks like there's a man who deserves a presidential commendation, sir.
是的
Yes.
是有人该得
And then some.
是的
Yeah.
是有人该得
And then some.
"今天国家一片震惊...
The nation is in shock today in the aftermath of last night's....
昨晚国会大厦遭到武装袭击...
The assault on the Capitol has reverberated around the world....
死亡人数未知 当局称所有袭击者都被击毙
The death toll is unknown. Authorities say all assailants were killed.
袭击者成功地突破了...
The attack was thwarted by a joint effort...
首都警察和联邦警探之后...
...from D. C. police and federal agencies.
一群武装歹徒成功渗透...
A group of armed assailants managed to penetrate security....
白宫消息证实总统安然无恙
Sources confirm the president is secure.
另外 国防部长德克...
Secretary of Defense George Deckert...
今天以最高军事荣誉获得安葬
... was buried with full military honors today.
国防部长德克在国会遇袭事件中
Secretary Deckert lost his life while trying to rescue the president...
为保护总统而献身
...during the attack on the Capitol.
他将作为民族英雄而名垂青史
He will be remembered as one of our nation's greatest heroes.
我爱死这个国家了
I love this town.
我们比任何时候都需要英雄
Now, more than ever, we need heroes.
因此 我很荣幸
So it is with great pride...
把议会荣誉勋章颁发给
... that I bestow this Congressional Medal of Honor...
凯利·克里斯托弗·斯蒂尔
...on Kyle Christopher Steele.
并把这个勋章颁发给一位无名英雄
And I hold this medal for the unknown soldier...
不管他现在身在何处
... wherever he may be.
战争打打停停
For wars come and go...
而我们的战士却是永恒不变的
...but my soldiers, they stay eternal.
总统刚刚引用了图帕克名句?
Did the president just quote Tupac?
这个混蛋偷了我的台词
Son of a bitch stole my line.
怎么?
So, what's this?
你又要走?
You out?
你了解我的 罗拉
You know me, Lo.
只有被警察追着的时候 我才过得舒服
I'm only good at 100-plus with a couple of cops on my tail.
而且你在这过得不错
And you got a good life here...
这就够我再回味九年的了
That ought to keep me going another nine years.
德瑞斯
D...
那车有多快?
...how fast did she go?
220 225
Two-twenty, 225.
在我的生命中 排名第二
The second-best ride of my life.
德瑞斯
D...
你忘了件东西
...you forgot something.
先生 我对下一任XXX有点建议
Sir, I've got some ideas for the next XXX.
这次总该轮到我挑了吧
I think it's my turn to choose now.
别争了 先生们 我来挑
Hold on, gentlemen. I pick the agents.
我想我们下次需要一个更加难以捉摸的
I think we need to go even further off the grid next time.
新形象 新模样
Fresh face. New model.
我已经有了最佳人选
I've got the perfect candidate.